Oh, wow!
Wow!
Shall I retire?
Yum!
Listen to the taste.
Oh no!
Hello, I'm Haruka Kato. I'm Inao Yanagi.
Today, I went undercover at an animation production company!
Yay!
I'm so happy!
You can see me in the background, though,
Ah! Just in time!
Today, right here.
We are here at Cloverworks.
I'm so happy to be here. I like a lot of anime.
What do you like?
Well, but there are many things.
I used to like "Hollymere".
Oh, I understand.
I like Holy Mia a lot.
What do you like?
Well, I'm not sure,
I liked McNabb and the original, and I like the anime a lot, too.
Oh, you were in the movie.
It just came on.
Oh, it's Hollymere.
It was a lot of pictures.
It's amazing.
Oh, I like Arline the Francis a lot, too.
I like it too.
My friends and I were addicted to watching it.
I was addicted to watching it with my friends when I was in high school.
I miss it.
I miss it, I really do.
Ah, I made it useful.
This place is kinda nice. I can watch it all the time.
I'm very happy about this project,
Trapezium, written by Kazumi Takayama, a first-term student of Nogizaka46, is going to be an anime movie.
It's amazing, isn't it?
It's amazing.
I'm really looking forward to it.
And the production company is Glover Work, right?
I wonder if it will come out if we wait a little bit.
I think it's going to come out.
It's going to come out...just watch.
Do you think it will come out?
Oh, no, it's just the video here.
Ahhh...
I love it.
Really.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh?
Oh?
Are you coming?
Thank you for watching.
Oh, my God! It's the month of May!
Oh, May!
With that in mind, we are going undercover this time!
I would like to introduce the person who will be guiding us today. Please do.
Please give us your best regards.
Please give me a warm welcome.
I am an animation producer at Kroworks. My name is Someno.
I am a producer of Trapezium.
I am in charge of Trapezium's producer.
Today, I would like to introduce various things in the company, focusing on Trapezium.
It's not often that I get a chance to do something like this.
I'm really looking forward to it, so thank you very much for your time.
I am here undercover, but where did you go first?
I would like to take you to the actual production site of the animation,
On the way there, there is a zone where posters of our past and future works are lined up,
Please take a moment to walk through the zone,
Is that OK with you?
I hope you will do it.
I can walk around like this.
What do you think?
I feel like I'm stepping in it.
I'm sure.
Ah!
Oh, wow!
Wow, there are so many!
There are so many.
Wow!
I see them. It's an orimi.
No, it's cute.
I like the atmosphere.
Nothing happens, but in the case of revolts, there is a kind of approaching and separating,
In the case of the piece, the ordinary life goes on and on,
But with Peace, it's just an ordinary day in the life, but there's a joke and a joke in it,
The "Peace" series has a lot of color, and you can really feel like you are in their world,
You can really feel like you're in the world of the characters.
I can understand.
I understand.
You can see the person's darkness,
You can see their darkness, right?
I can see it.
It's not light.
I like it because it's realistic.
I understand.
Ah!
It's the Spire family.
Cute, this post.
Really?
Anya's face.
I like it.
It's cute.
Lately, I've been hanging out with my colleague.
I've been with her a lot lately.
Anya looks just like Anya.
Maybe they look alike.
I'm sure.
I don't know, I can't see Anya in some way.
I can't see Anya, I can't see her.
Anya, Anya.
I don't change much.
Not much change.
Her mood doesn't change either.
She's cute.
But you did cosplay, didn't you?
Yes, I did.
I'm sorry.
I was excited without permission, wasn't I?
Oh, the blue pig.
Blue Pig is quite local.
Indeed.
That's right.
It's Kamakura, so it's a little place that I used to go to a lot, and it's important to me.
I've never seen it.
Really?
When I saw the illustration, I thought it might be a normal love story, but it's not like that, is it?
It's more like a moving story.
Yes, that's right.
I thought it was going to be a cartoonish story, but it turns out that I started to cry a lot when I started watching it.
I see.
But I really don't think this is a work that I would recommend to anyone.
Yes, it is.
Please watch it.
If you have time.
I'll watch it.
I'll try to watch it.
Really.
I won't watch it.
Yes, aumenta.
I'm sorry, it looks good.
Oh, here it is!
Trapezium!
When the touch was really misunderstood...
The picture is so beautiful.
The light is so beautiful.
I love works with beautiful light.
Trapezium is so beautifully lit that it even has the catchphrase "humans can glow".
The director is very conscious of the light.
The director made the film with an awareness of light effects.
I draw pictures as much as I feel like it, but it's difficult to draw light.
I draw pictures only to the extent that I feel like it, but I think it's really difficult to draw light.
I like the way the lines change color.
I like the way the lines change color as they get closer to the light, like white and yellow.
I can't do it at all, even though I know what it is in my head.
It's amazing.
This is the room now.
It's called Genga-san.
This is the room where the director, who directs each square, is working.
I'd like to show you the zone for the Trapezium artists.
Yes, sir.
That's great.
Excuse me.
Wow.
What do you see when you look at the seats?
I didn't.
It's not running right now, so...
That's great.
Well, you know, most of them are digital now.
I'm talking about 70% to 80% digital.
So we have these LCD tablets and things like that.
and monitors to view setting materials and reference materials.
and a monitor to look at setting and reference materials.
I see.
Can you give us a glimpse of what it's like to work on Genga?
Can I see what Genga is like?
Yes, I would.
I'd love to show you the original of the first cut of the Trapezium photo.
Oh, my gosh! Wow!
That's great!
It's called an original picture here, so I'm sure there's a lot of information on it.
I'm sure there are a lot of different ways to paint it.
This is also the section that gives instructions for the actual coloring process.
The original drawing is also the section that gives instructions for later processes.
How many seconds does this take?
This cut is about 10 seconds long.
If you take a look at this, you can see that there are dots between the numbers 1, 2, and 3.
You see the dots between the numbers 1,2,3?
This is the animation.
The animation is to fill in these dots one by one with the movement in between the dots.
It's a simple calculation, but it's about five times or even ten times the amount of work you have to do.
I think it's really a matter of course when making animation.
It may be a matter of course when making animation, but it's not the same as drawing a picture.
It's a different picture, isn't it?
It's a different picture.
The lines are not blurred.
Do you think it's easy to get the message across?
I understand.
It's not loose.
I made an animated circle once since school.
The circles are all different sizes.
They don't connect.
Prapedium is a movie... and it's long.
How many pages do you write?
I made the film one by one.
There are about 1300 cuts.
Each cut is called an original picture.
This is just a rough average.
But it's about 20 pictures.
Let's say that there are 1,000 cuts, that's 20,000 pictures.
20,000 original pictures
And if we convert that into a movie, we can see the number like 60,000, 70,000, 80,000, and so on....
Wow!
Yes, sir.
This room is called the finishing room.
I hope you can see the process of adding color to the characters.
I'd like you to take a look at the outside work.
Yes, please.
Thank you.
Good morning.
That's great.
I've just heard that you've made an amazing number of sheets.
I'd like to introduce you to a few of them.
But we have to paint them one by one at a high speed.
That's right.
The speed of the finisher's operation is really fast.
It's amazing to watch.
It's amazing.
That's great.
I see, you have to paint the lines too.
How long does it take for one original picture?
It depends on the subject, but 10 minutes for one video.
That's right.
And how many pictures was that?
I mean, it's very long.
So next time you watch an animation
I'd like you to take a look at the credits section and see if you can see the name of the person or number of people involved in the finishing process.
I'd like you to look at the number of people involved in the finishing process in the credits section.
I think it would be good to get a sense of how many people worked on it.
It would be nice to get a sense of how many people it took to make it.
I've always wondered what the finishing touches were.
I didn't even know what it was.
Oh, it's done!
That's great.
You know, you said it didn't take long... to get here, and we just talked for a minute.
And now it's over.
This is the section that we're working on now, the filming section.
I'm going to combine the character material that I just created in the finishing section with the background material that you can see behind it.
and the background material that you can see in the background.
As you can see, the character is still in the process of being perfected.
We're still working on perfecting the character, so we're going to have to have a photographer who can take a good look at the background and the character.
This, by the way, is called "Gradience.
What's gradience?
Gradient?
It's a gradient that has two pieces of color information.
I see.
And this is what we're going to do at the end of the shoot.
We don't just put a background.
Animation is not just about placing a background, it's about creating a space.
So we added light effects in this section of the filming.
The sparkling clothes...
The clothes are sparkling.
It's true.
Because it's a live scene, light comes in from various directions.
So we're going to add that to the scene.
We're going to have to do that, too.
It's a lot of brain work.
That's great.
There's a lot of work to do.
By the way, the live scene at Trapidium
It's the first time it's been shown in Japan.
What?
Oh, my.
Oh, my God, it's so important.
This?
This.
I've never seen it before.
I've already seen it.
It's so cute!
I've been working on the camera work for the live part.
I'll let you know when it's done.
What? I'm so excited!
The real professionals can see it.
It's good.
I was just explaining a little bit earlier.
I was wondering if you two could experience the process of making a video.
Experience?
Oh, my gosh.
If you actually do the video in its entirety, the first shot would probably take hours.
A part of it...
It's called "Mepatsuki".
It's one of the most important movements in the animation.
I'm going to show you a video to experience it.
Here it is.
I'm making it watermarked now.
Eyes open and eyes closed.
I have to make them crackle.
Oh, I see.
When I'm here, I have to draw the middle eye, which is called the middle eye.
Oh, great.
You mean you have to draw in between?
Huh?
Ha!
Huh? Huh? How's it going?
It's hard.
Oh, my God, Splat.
That's great.
You've got a great sense of humor.
Yay!
This is hard.
It's just like it is now.
It's amazing.
It's alive.
I'd love to be an animator.
I'm thinking about changing careers.
It's fun.
It's nice to be able to draw my favorite cartoons.
It's nice, isn't it?
It sounds like a lot of work.
I'll draw the next anime.
...
So this is what you mean.
It's moving.
It's so cute, it's crackling.
That's great.
It's crackling.
That's great. Thank you very much.
That's great.
I did it.
Wow.
That's great!
This is the one you wrote for me, too.
We can use this already!
That's great!
It's amazing.
It's alive.
I really like anime.
I used to...
I used to watch it.
But even recently...
I've learned that people make anime like this.
It was fun to learn about that, too.
Hey, the back side of the back side of the back side of the back side of the back side of the back side of the back side
It was so cool.
I thought it was really cool.
You got a new job, didn't you?
I don't know if I'll ever go back.
Maybe I'll get a job here.
You're going to be sad.
Hey, I know this is personal, but...
I never studied.
I've never studied at all.
But if I didn't get into NAGASAKA...
I would have gone to art school.
I always wanted to work for a company like this.
It's amazing, isn't it?
I feel like both of my dreams have come true.
It's a wonderful job.
It's a wonderful profession.
Thank you very much.
Please subscribe to our channel and give us a rating!
See you later.
I just watched it a few minutes ago.
It was so beautiful and so much fun.
I hope you guys can watch it.
You were watching it while holding it?
I was holding it and looking at it like this.
I found a scene that we kind of painted.
There? There? I was like...
I was like, "Oh, there it is.
I thought, "There it is.
I was so moved.
It's because I went to Clover Arks first.
I was able to enjoy it a little bit differently because I went to Clover Arks first.
I was able to enjoy the scenes that you showed me.
And the story was wonderful, too.
I heard that Mr. Okayama is here right now, so I'm looking forward to seeing the movie.
Anyway
I'll be right back.
It's nice to meet you.
I'd like to give you some feedback.
I'd like to share my thoughts with you.
I'm off.
I'll be back.
Go, go, go.
Excuse me.
It's been a while.
Good night, I thought yesterday, didn't I?
Good night.
Thank you very much.
I'm sorry, I'm taking a selfie.
Do you mind?
Of course.
Not like this, not like this.
It's bright.
It's good, it's good, it's good.
I've seen it.
Thank you very much.
It was a lot of fun.
Nice to meet you.
I've just seen the movie, and I'd like to give you a fresh impression.
The catchphrase "Humans are glowing!
The light in the animation was really beautiful.
The light in the animation was really beautiful, and in the story, when there is light, there are also shadows, aren't there?
As an idol, there are a lot of things going on.
Sometimes the emotions can be happy and joyful.
But then the darker side of the story comes out.
I don't know...
The way it's portrayed...
I felt like my heart was shaken along with them.
I saw it from the perspective of Nogizaka as an idol, but I also saw it from the perspective of myself.
I also saw it from my perspective as an idol, but also as a person who is not an idol.
The way each character's heart moves is completely different.
I felt like I was watching real life.
It was a lot of fun!
I'm glad.
The title "Lavezium" also means "unequal-sided rectangle".
It's not a square, so I wanted to make it messy.
I didn't want the story to be about characters who get along.
If you draw only good girls, they'll do good things, right?
You want them to be good and do good things.
That's right, that's right.
It's because my group was so wonderful.
I wondered how I could draw such a messy group.
I'm so happy because it's what I was aiming for.
Thanks, Kaki-chan!
Oh, I thought this picture was precious.
The trees don't overlap.
You know, it's true.
I'm kind of in the middle, so it's kind of weird.
Kaki-ya!
Kakiya, you're a big sister, aren't you?
I see.
That's right.
When you read a novel, you create it in your head.
Why did you give it to me?
I read it.
Thank you.
That way, you can only do what's in your head.
So when I see the images, or the characters in motion...
I see... it's kind of new.
Yes, it's quite different, and the story is different too.
I'm sure that if you could see the scratches, it would be the right answer.
But it's like...
So there's a pattern to it.
I also had a longing to be an idol.
But I didn't say so.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Not really.
I didn't tell people around me.
I was with them.
Even though I was with them, I still admired them.
The longer I admired idols, the more and more
The longer I admired idols, the more they became a part of my life.
It's because they're already amazing people.
That's why I wanted to be an idol.
When I became an idol, I felt like there was a right way to be an idol.
I feel like this is what idols are all about.
That's why I feel like I'm not an idol.
I'm not an idol.
Like I'm an idol who has to stand up to them.
I had already created the right answer in my mind.
So...
The four of us, east, west, south, north and south, are all heading in the same direction, but we all have different personalities.
They see the same thing in different ways.
I think it's because I'm an idol.
I felt like I was being affirmed.
I felt like they understood how I felt.
That's why I was really saved.
I was so moved.
But I'm happy.
I think so.
I think so too.
Oh, come here.
This one...
This one.
Who's got a lot of good shots.
Thank you.
I'm usually modest.
I'm never successful.
Because someone else was on my left or something.
I didn't have enough room in my hand.
Except for myself
Heh heh heh heh.
I wish I had a selfie stick or something.
I wish we had a selfie stick.
I didn't have a selfie stick.
Sorry to interrupt.
Are you streaming?
Oh, we're just streaming.
Yes, I'm sorry to interrupt.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Special Jesus.
No, I'm sorry.
Thank you very much.
Well then
Uh, bye.
Oh, bye.
see you next time
bye
Skinny darling
Subtitles Uh
Eh
Recommendation Nah
a
Thank you for watching